Civilization is born of knowledge
Medeniyet bilgiden doğar.
But so, too, can knowledge be its demise
Ama aynı şekilde bilgi, medeniyetin ölümü de olabilir.
A disaster caught us unaware
Bir felaket bizi habersiz yakaladı.
It was knowledge that did not belong to this world
Her şey bu dünyaya ait olmayan bir bilgi yüzünden oldu.
King Deshret brought this forbidden knowledge into our world
Kral Deshret bu yasak bilgiyi dünyamıza getirdi
And it quickly spread like a plague
ve bu bilgi bir salgın gibi çabucak yayıldı.
People's minds were filled with crazed whispers
İnsanların zihninde çılgın fısıltılar yankılanmaya başladı.
Dark gray scales spread across their bodies
Bedenleri koyu gri pullarla kaplandı.
Even the land was stripped of its vigor
Toprak bile yaşamla olan bağını kesmişti.
Only a desperate, deathly silence remained
Geriye sadece umutsuz, ölümcül bir sessizlik kalmıştı.
Were it not for Greater Lord Rukkhadevata from the forests
Ormanlardan gelen Mahadevi Rukkhadevata olmasaydı
The damage would have been irreversible
alınan hasarın geri dönüşü olmazdı.
She summoned the priests to build temples
Tapınakları inşa etmeleri için rahipleri çağırdı
And infused into them the divine power of life
ve onlara yaşamın ilahi gücünü aşıladı.
The disaster was miraculously tempered
Böylece felaket mucizevi bir şekilde önlendi
And the embers of our civilization were preserved in Aaru Village
ve medeniyetimizin kıvılcımları Aaru Köyü'nde korunabildi.
Alas, the miracle could not last
Ne var ki bu mucize sonsuza dek süremezdi...
As long as forbidden knowledge continued to exist
Yasaklı bilgi var olmaya devam ettikçe
It would forever blight this world
bu dünyaya felaket getirmeye devam edecekti.
In the end
Nihayetinde...
The proud king of the desert... my eternal lord...
Çölün gururlu kralı... Benim ebedi lordum
Chose to sacrifice himself
bu uğurda kendini feda etmeyi seçti.
I have spent my whole life since guarding one of these many temples
O zamandan beri hayatımı bu tapınaklardan birini korumaya adamıştım.
As I close my eyes for the final time
Gözlerimi son kez yumduğumda
The sight of that noble deity will appear in my vision once more...
o asil tanrıçayı bir kez daha göreceğim.
In helping King Deshret to eradicate forbidden knowledge
Kral Deshret'in yasak bilgiyi ortadan kaldırmasına yardım ederken
She exhausted her strength, and her form became that of a small child
gücü tükendi ve bedeni bir çocuğun görünümünü aldı.
How strange
Ne kadar da tuhaf...
Now that I think of her, I no longer have any fear of death...
Onu düşünürken artık ölüm korkusu gelmiyor aklıma...
For I sense that
Ebedi uykuma yattığımda
The spirit of life will abide with me during my eternal sleep
yaşamın ruhu da yanımda olacakmış gibi hissediyorum.
Children of the desert
Ey çölün çocukları!
Cling no longer to past grievances
Mazinin kinlerine takılıp kalmayın.
But hold tight to the memory
Ve sadece yapılan iyiliklerin anısına